So, let's start off by talking about
food. What's your favorite food? Um, I
really love Asian food cuz I live in
England, so it's harder to get Asian
food around, but I like spicy,
flavorful, and like just generally
savory food. Do you cook a lot at home?
Not as much as I would like to. I would
love to cook more cuz I actually enjoy
the process of cooking, but I just cook
out of convenience and like cuz um every
day I've got to, you know, make sure I
get my work done and then cook for my
kids, which um takes a lot of time.
Sometimes we get takeaway, but they like
it, you know. What are popular takeaway
meals in your local area? Fish and
chips. It's a favorite with everyone.
So, you know, that's an easy option, but
um generally because of my own
preference, I love, you know, just to
get Thai and Vietnamese. You know, this
is something that I could, you know,
just get around my local area. It's very
easily sourced. How often do you eat
fast food? I try to eat really
healthily, but then I tend to go down
the filio fish, McDonald's uh route when
I'm traveling. So, I suppose only once
every few months. Now, let's talk about
seasons of the year. What's your
favorite season of the year? Well, um I
love anytime when the sun starts to come
out. So, around spring or early summer
before it gets too hot, you know, I just
love a little bit of vitamin D and it
makes me happier as well. So, that is um
definitely better than the winter. What
do you do when it gets too hot in the
summer? Hide. I tend to also, you know,
go into any kind of buildings with air
conditioning and I have to fan on every
night when it's really hot. So, yeah,
when it gets really hot in the summer,
you know, I really need a lot of like
fans and, you know, kind of just
anything I can hold with me when I go
out as well. At what time of year do you
normally go on holiday? I try to go
outside of the um school holiday season,
but because I have kids, you know, we
tend to have to go during, you know, the
the you know, when when there's term
breaks, you know, when when the school
breaks. But, um my favorite time of
going away would be during Christmas,
you know, cuz um I much prefer to be in
a warmer climate when it's really really
cold. So, yeah, this is just that time
before or after Christmas. Have you ever
been on holiday somewhere very cold?
Yes, I love Norway. You know, it it was
um amazing. It was just everything was
like a picture perfect postcard, you
know. You could see the fields in the
distance and the what you call them
icebergs.
Um it was an experience, you know, and
to ri to to ride the husky sled, you
know, was also an amazing experience for
me. Now, let's talk about clothes. Where
do you buy most of your clothes? I would
like to do, you know, clothes shopping
in the shop, but the reality is most of
us do it online now, you know, and I um
get my clothes from Zara and ASOS cuz I
just love the hip and trendy but also
timeless look. How often do you buy
clothes for yourself? I buy it more
often than I should because I use online
shopping and clothes shopping as a form
of you know like dopamine hit for me. So
it's it's um for me I I love to express
myself through my clothes. So um because
of that then I need to find different
clothes for different occasion very
often. Have you always had the same
taste in clothes? No, I have not. Um cuz
I see myself as um different identities
throughout my life, you know, before I
became a mom, during and then also after
when work became something that I could
express myself, you know, true. So yeah,
I've I've had different fashion tastes,
you know, throughout the ages. Now,
let's talk about social media. Which
social media sites do you use? I use uh
Instagram and LinkedIn because I feel
like um I run a business and that's
where my target audience are. You know,
I build a community through Instagram
and then on LinkedIn it's where I work
on my business to business um leads. How
much time do you spend on social media?
Way too much. I shouldn't be spending so
much time but I find that it is um once
you visit you know social media and you
post something it's also about engaging
with people to ensure that you know you
build relationships. So yeah a couple of
hours a day. Is there anything you
dislike about social media? I dislike
the addictive quality about it you know
because so many of us are connected you
know through a tablet or a device now
and social media is our form of
communication. So it's becoming even
though it seems like you're being
connected to loads and loads of people,
the actual quality of your relationships
with your immediate sphere, you know,
kind of, you know, kind of falls by the
side. So yeah, that's one bad side to
it. That's the end of part one of the
speaking test. So now we're going to
move on to part two of the speaking
test. I'm going to give you a Q card.
You'll have one minute to read the Q
card and prepare your answer. Feel free
to make any notes during that 1 minute.
At the end of the 1 minute, I'll let you
know and I'll ask you to speak for up to
2 minutes. Is that all clear? Of course.
Okay. Here is your Q card
and I'll start the 1 minute preparation
time. Here's a pen if you want to make
any notes.
So, please speak for up to two minutes
on this topic, please. Okay. So, a job
that I really enjoyed is being a speaker
and a storyteller. And I love doing this
job now because when I was growing up, I
love writing little stories and, you
know, just connecting with people and
having conversations. But I never
thought that I could become a speaker
one day. Um, I started my career, you
know, in STEM and then ventured through
16 different industries cuz I didn't
really know where in the world of work I
fitted into. But eventually I realized
that all this became really useful for
me to gain all the skills that I needed,
you know, in communication and brought
it all together in a field that I was
deeply passionate about. That allowed me
to channel what I really love about my
work and a topic that I love, you know,
to make a difference in people's lives.
Being a speaker is the perfect place to
do this because you could influence
people's thoughts and inspire positivity
in people's lives, which is something
that you could do in other places, but
the impact is so much more immediate and
you are affecting people in such a big
way and affecting a bigger audience as
well whilst you're doing it. And this is
something that I'm very lucky to be able
to do now. And I don't take it for
granted and know that the journey for me
to get here has been really long. But um
I'm deeply grateful for being given this
opportunity. And why I like it also is
that to be able to connect with people
in in in a topic that is so personal
about me mental health and well-being.
you know, we're in some way or other,
you know, we're all struggling um in
life.
But thank you very much. That's the end
of the two. Thank you. I could have gone
on.
You could. So, now we're going to move
on to part three of the speaking test
and we're going to continue to talk
about careers. What factors do you think
are important when choosing a career? I
think it's really really important that
we are interested in what we're doing
and because if you're not interested
then it is there's absolutely no chance
that you're going to be able to have
longevity in that career. We should also
choose an industry where there's a
potential for you to really grow within
that industry because as we're moving
now into the future of work, you know,
technology is very quickly replacing
people, you know, especially artificial
intelligence, it's threatening a lot of
jobs like writing and recruiting and
connecting, you know, with with people.
So we need to look at how you know the
industry that you're going into has got
the potential to go beyond that you know
technological capa capacity. What can
you bring as a human you know that no
technology or anyone could replace you
you know if you were to go into it. Why
do you think some people fail in some
careers? I think one of the main drivers
I think for for people is money and when
you do anything solely because of money
then it will never work. And the reason
people fail I think the biggest reason
is because they have failed to align
their identity with their work cuz we
spend a third of our lives you know in
work. So a very big proportion of it you
know needs to feel fulfilled and you can
only be fulfilled if you're you
understand you know what what you like
authentically inside you know and and
then you know go into a career but then
the reality is that most people then you
know jump in and figure it out explore
and then we work it out you know in
hindsight I guess that's what life's
about. Now let's talk about working from
home in the future. Do you think most
people will work from home? I think it's
just it definitely seems that way anyway
you know after the pandemic you know
hybrid working is becoming more common
and a lot of organizations are offering
fully remote working now which a lot of
people like but there are also people
who like human interactions like
connections you know people who live by
themselves or you know just need some
accountability. So being amongst people
could be a good thing but I think if
technology would to replace you know a
lot of the work you know then people
would actually eventually do more remote
work. And finally what are the
disadvantages of working from home?
Well, I guess it's the disconnection,
you know, from from people, but also not
getting accountability for your work
because I I think working from home
requires us to have some a sense of
agency, you know, and some level of
organization, which um some people might
not have. So, we're dealing with
different personalities here. And I
think if we were to ask people what they
prefer, then there's a better chance,
you know, for like either remote or not,
not remote work to work. That's the end
of the speaking test. Well done. Right.
I hope you enjoyed that band N
performance. What you should do now is
watch one of these videos. If you want
to compare band N with a band 8
performance, click on this video. Or if
you want to know why that was band nine
and exactly what you can do to improve
to the score that you need, click on
this video where I'll explain the key
differences between lower bands and
higher bands.